episode where I cover four things, what's on my mind this week? Recommended reading
something fun and something to help your systems. This is the show that helps overwhelmed
coaches, consultants, and service providers build systems so their business doesn't
depend on them. Hopefully this week's curation gets you thinking about your own systems
Before you close the laptop for the weekend, I'm your host, Joe Casabona, and here's
what's on my mind for August 21st, 2026,
second most popular post in the last 90 days
behind only a post to Doist paid to boost.
It's a contrarian view that I don't feel should be contrarian.
If you didn't write it, it's not yours.
I'll touch more on this in the recommended reading segment, but ultimately it boils
down to this.
If you have an idea and outsource it to an LLM to write about that idea, it's not
or as I put it, MySpace, but only for college students back in 2003.
But as I said, you'll get more of that in the next segment.
This LinkedIn post was the catalyst for what's actually on my mind this week, conscientious
AI use. This was a term proposed to me by my mastermind group. Shout out to,
Jen, Liz, Rahul, Tanya, and Mike. And I've been thinking about it ever since.
I've written a lot about AI over the last couple of years, but I've always been hesitant
to brand myself as an AI person, even a contrarian one because I didn't want to be
viewed as taking advantage of some ai. Gold rush tools come and go, methods come
and go, but it's really the core principles that matter when you're doing something
that said more people are asking me about it and it's becoming a legitimate part
The other event that is pushing me towards this thinking about conscientious AI usage
is that Claude has broken spectacularly for me this week.
Basically from when I started my weekly planning on Sunday up until right before
I hit record every day. Claude has given me a different problem. Whatever changes
they made in last week's updates has screwed up a bunch of my skills and projects.
and for some this would put a halt to their work as they rely so heavily on AI to
do the work for them. I know this because when Claude is down, there are people who
legitimately cannot work a lot, say This must be a sign to go outside. I say a sign
to go outside is you want to go outside,
not the thing you've outsourced your thinking to is down.
One tenant of conscientious AI usage is that you're using it for specific tasks
and not craft
meaning that when the large language model breaks your whole business
or your whole work day isn't
that you don't have to spend a bunch of time fixing the thing so the work can get
done
that you should be able to continue working
ai. That's love-hate dot ai. I am actually shocked that domain was available.
that is going to be where all of my AI writing podcast episodes and YouTube videos
will be. By the way, when I say AI writing, I mean things I wrote about ai, not things
I had AI write.
And of course, if you have something on your mind, what do you think about conscientious
Okay, let's get to the recommended reading. This is from Dan Morin over at Six Colors.
Several people have asked me what I think about the lexical watermark that Anthropic
is adding to writing in its new models.
my most glib answer has been, I'm not worried about it because I'm not using LLMs
to write for me. I don't think anyone should. So this is actually, Annette, good
for me,
but I was also very confused to read John Gruber's very angry take about it.
He is so mad that this watermarking is happening. He is so mad that AI has stolen
to not use it.
And truth be told, I've never been a huge fan of John Gruber's work, though I do
respect what he's done. I mean, he's like an
OG
actually get paid to blog Blogger.
My take is actually much closer to Dan Morin's at Six Colors and it is today's recommended
reading. So I'm gonna quote this directly here.
If this does truly make AI generated text worse, well good.
A lot of people are already willing to accept what an LLM turns out as good enough.
I agree wholeheartedly with this quote, and I feel a lot of the backlash is revolving
around two aspects of AI writing. The first is that AI is changing the words to make
if you are so concerned about the word choices, which you should be,
so passionate
that we shouldn't let AI write for us.
'cause when we are letting a machine
communicate what we feel are important thoughts,
We are robbing people of our actual thoughts.
And so we should be concerned about the words that are being used on our behalf.
And so if this watermarking thing gets worse and more, more audacious, great, we
should all use AI writing less.
But the other side of it
is that people are being outed for using AI in their writing. Like, why are we mad
about this? This is a good thing.
If you are unashamedly using AI to do your writing, then you should disclose that
you used it.
If you think it's so great that I just give Claude an idea and my team of agents
makes it sound just like me, which it doesn't sound like
you,
you are diluting yourself if you believe that.
Give credit where credit is due,
because otherwise, in my view, it is
It's not just a means to an end.
It's a universally important skill.
Not everyone needs to be an incredible writer.
Not everyone needs to be Shakespeare or whoever,
but we should all be able to state our own thoughts.
We should all be able to think through an opinion,
not just give AI a vague idea and have it write it for us.
Okay,
well, with all that, let's move on to something fun.
That's something fun as Halo three.
Last weekend, it was a rainy, sleepy weekend.
As we in the household in southeastern pa as we prepare to go back to school,
we're tired from the summer,
so we decided to have a family screen day.
The kids enjoyed movies and games and I dusted off the old Xbox, paid $24 for a month
of Game Pass and I booted up Halo three.
I don't play video games much these days. I mean, I do like the
mobile games from New York Times. I play Immaculate Grid
But
true blue video games, right? These would consume large portions of my days in high
school and college.
Sometimes
That's why I love old school games like Halo or Gears of War, these run and gun games,
you know you're going the right way as long as you see more bad guys
and there are no side quests or massive customizations. I knew Call of Duty left
me behind when I had to like pick all the gear I had and the type of soldier I wanted
to be. I just wanna pick up a gun that I run over and and use it. I don't wanna have
to think about every single attribute of my character.
and October are going to be very busy for me,
Okay, let's move on to something to help your systems.
And I wanna talk about something I did this week with
like upsettingly little
about what makes a good lead magnet, but I worry that they'll saturate the market
soon. And here's why.
Generally, quizzes have been something aspirational for me
due to the time constraints and the fact that I didn't want to pay for all of the
industry leading services, right? I think like SCORE app is, is
50 or a hundred bucks a month or something like that,
but large language models have changed that
Earlier this week in conjunction with my thinking around conscientious AI usage,
I decided to make an Are you suffering from AI Brain Rot quiz.
I have the aforementioned hub of content over@lovehate.ai, which I fed into Claude
to help me make a short eight question quiz evaluating my four dimensions of AI brain
rot, which is using it reflexively. That is to say, not thinking of a problem for
more than a few minutes before asking a large language model,
talking to AI instead of people. So asking like, what does my audience want? Instead
because you didn't come up with something, you're actually not really committed to
it. You're just burning tokens and not really thinking about the the things that
you're doing.
And using AI as a coach, and we know that AI cannot advise because it cannot have
opinions because it's not thinking,
it is doing word association.
So it looks at the quiz, looks at my four dimensions of AI brain rock, and then gives
the user a score
and then the user will get a resource and recommendations for conscientious AI usage.
is A PDF and it was generated from a markdown file that I wrote using my design system
and brand guidelines that I gave to Claude Design.
The most kind of,
I'll say craft work that Claude did here
was come up with the scoring and questions based on my writing,
and then I had it mark all of the places where it created placeholder copy so I can
go in and change it.
Claude Code then wrote the application and ran its automated tests, and then I tested
it independently and wired it up to kit.com, which is my email service provider,
and it would not have looked nearly as good.
Instead, it took me a couple of hours between meetings because Claude already had
all of my content,
knows my AP well, knows, quote unquote
has. My approach in context,
is connected to my kit account
and is connected to Netlify.
My last task in this project, which,
should be done before you are hearing this,
is to review all of the copy with fresh eyes,
then I'll feel comfortable promoting it widely. But for now, you can find it
at Brain Rot streamlined,
FM
But that's it for this episode of the Friday wrap up from Streamline Solopreneur.
These episodes are about taking more time off, especially
on the weekends, and this has been an AI intensive episode. So if you wanna be more
can be using it more conscientiously.
Thanks so much for listening to this episode, and until next time, I hope you find
some space in your weekend.